Guide to the Lillian D. Wald Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VII: Nursing
  - Visiting Nurse Service, Executive Committee: correspondence. 1917-1919 (Box 86, Folder 1.4)
  - Visiting Nurse Service, Executive Committee: correspondence, 1920-1921 (Box 86, Folder 1.5)
  - Visiting Nurse Service, Executive Committee: correspondence, 1922 (Box 86, Folder 1.6)
  - Visiting Nurse Service, Executive Committee: correspondence, 1923 (Box 86, Folder 1.7)
  - Visiting Nurse Service. Executive Committee: correspondence, 1924-1927 (Box 86, Folder 1.8)
  - Visiting Nurse Service. Executive Committee; lists, memoranda, etc. (Box 86, Folder 1.9)
  - Visiting Nurse Service, Executive Committee: minutes. 1915 (Box 86, Folder 1.10)
  - Visiting Nurse Service, Executive Committee: minutes. 1916 (Box 86, Folder 1.11)
  - Visiting Nurse Service, Executive Committee: minutes, 1917 (Box 86, Folder 1.12)
  - Visiting Nurse Service, Executive Committee: minutes. 1918 (Box 86, Folder 1.13)
  - Visiting Nurse Service. Executive Committee: minutes, 1919 (Box 86, Folder 1.14)
  - Visiting Nurse Service. Executive Committee: minutes. 1920 (Box 86, Folder 1.15)
  - Visiting Nurse Service. Executive Committee: minutes. 1921 (Box 86, Folder 1.16)
    On Reel 100 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Visiting Nurse Service. Executive Committee: minutes. 1922 (Box 86, Folder 1.17)
  - Visiting Nurse Service, Executive Committee: minutes. 1923 (Box 87, Folder 1.1)
  - Visiting Nurse Service, Executive Committee: minutes, 1924 (Box 87, Folder 1.2)
  - Visiting Nurse Service. Executive Committee: minutes. 1930 (Box 87, Folder 1.3)
  - Visiting Nurse Service, Executive Committee: minutes, 1931 (Box 87, Folder 1.4)
  - Visiting Nurse Service, Executive Committee: minutes, 1932 (Box 87, Folder 1.5)
  - Visiting Nurse Service, financial appeal (Box 87, Folder 1.6)
  - Visiting Nurse Service. manual (Box 87, Folder 1.7)
  - Visiting Nurse Service, maternity appeal (Box 87, Folder 1.8)
    On Reel 101 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Visiting Nurse Service, printed material: clippings (Box 87, Folder 1.9)
  - Visiting Nurse Service, printed material: pamphlets, miscellaneous (Box 87, Folder 1.10)
  - Visiting Nurse Service. publicity (Box 87, Folder 1.11)
  - Visiting Nurse Service, publicity: press releases, articles (Box 87, Folder 1.12)
  - Visiting Nurse Service, publicity: speeches (Box 87, Folder 1.13)
  - Visiting Nurse Service; reports, miscellaneous (Box 87, Folder 1.14)
  - Visiting Nurse Service. Staten Island Branch (Box 87, Folder 1.15)
- Series VIII: Peace Movement
  - General; articles. Speeches, reports, etc. (Box 88, Folder 1.1)
  - General, correspondence (Box 88, Folder 1.2)
  - General, printed materials: clippings (Box 88, Folder 1.3)
  - General, printed materials: pamphlets (Box 88, Folder 1.4)
  - American Union Against Militarism. bulletins (Box 88, Folder 2.1)
  - American Union Against Militarism, correspondence: 1915 (Box 88, Folder 2.2)
    On Reel 102 of the Wald Microfilm
  - American Union Against Militarism. correspondence: 1916 (Box 88, Folder 2.3)
  - American Union Against Militarism. correspondence: 1917 (Box 88, Folder 2.4)
  - American Union Against Militarism. correspondence: 1918-1920 (Box 88, Folder 2.5)
  - American Union Against Militarism; memos, reports, releases, etc. (Box 88, Folder 2.6)
  - American Union Against Militarism. minutes: 1916 (Box 88, Folder 2.7)
  - American Union Against Militarism. minutes: 1917 (Box 88, Folder 2.8)
  - American Union Against Militarism, printed material (Box 88, Folder 2.9)
  - Anti-preparedness. clippings: I (Box 88, Folder 3.1)
  - Anti-preparedness, clippings: 2 (Box 88, Folder 3.2)
    On Reel 103 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Anti-preparedness; correspondence. reports, pamphlets (Box 88, Folder 3.3)
  - Citizens Service Bureau (Box 89, Folder 1.1)
  - Disarmament. 1914 (Box 89, Folder 2.1)
  - Disarmament. 1915 (Box 89, Folder 2.2)
  - Disarmament, 1916 (Box 89, Folder 2.3)
  - Disarmament, 1917 (Box 89, Folder 2.4)
  - Disarmament, 1918-1922 (Box 89, Folder 2.5)
  - Disarmament, 1931-1932 and no dale (Box 89, Folder 2.6)
  - Germany (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Henry Street Settlement meetings correspondence (Box 89, Folder 4.1)
  - Henry Street Settlement meetings, minutes and lists: 1914 (Box 89, Folder 4.2)
  - Henry Street Settlement meetings, minutes and lists: 191 S (Box 89, Folder 4.3)
  - Henry Street Settlement meetings, minutes and lists: 1916-1917 and no date (Box 89, Folder 4.4)
  - Henry Street Settlement. peace activities: 1932-1933 (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - League of Nations (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Limitation of Armament. American League to Limit Armaments (Box 89, Folder 7.1)
  - Limitation of Armament? correspondence (Box 89, Folder 7.2)
  - Limitation of Armament; memoranda, statements. etc. (Box 89, Folder 7.3)
  - Limitation of Armament, printed materials (Box 89, Folder 7.4)
    On Reel 104 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Mexico, 1916 (Box 89, Folder 8.1)
  - Mexico, 1917 (Box 89, Folder 8.2)
  - Mexico, 1919 (Box 89, Folder 8.3)
  - Mexico, 1920-1929 and no date (Box 89, Folder 8.4)
  - National Council for the Prevention of War (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - New York Peace Society (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - Overman Committee (Box 89, Folder 11)
  - Prohibition of war (Box 89, Folder 12)
  - "Survey" Committee (minutes) (Box 89, Folder 13)
  - War Resisters' League (Box 89, Folder 14)
- Series IX: Public Health
  - General, 1911-1914 (Box 90, Folder 1.1)
  - General, 1916-1918 (Box 90, Folder 1.2)
  - General, 1920-1927 (Box 90, Folder 1.3)
  - General, 1928-1931 (Box 90, Folder 1.4)
  - American Public Health Association (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - American Social Hygiene Association (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Bellevue-Yorkville Health Demonstration, 1926 (Box 90, Folder 4.1)
  - Bellevue-Yorkville Health Demonstration. 1927 (Box 90, Folder 4.2)
  - Bellevue-Yorkville Health Demonstration. 1928 (Box 90, Folder 4.3)
  - Bellevue-Yorkville Health Demonstration, 1929 (Box 90, Folder 4.4)
  - Bellevue-Yorkville Health Demonstration. 1930-1932 (Box 90, Folder 4.5)
  - Child hygiene (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Committee on Neighborhood Health Development (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Education Program for Garment Workers (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Hospitals (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - Infant morta1ity (Box 90, Folder 9)
  - Infantile paralysis. General (Box 90, Folder 10.1)
  - Infantile paralysis, New York City Department of Health (Box 90, Folder 10.2)
  - Infantile paralysis, New York City Department of Public Charities (Box 90, Folder 10.3)
  - Infantile paralysis, New York Committee on After Care (Box 90, Folder 10.4)
  - Infantile paralysis, printed materials: clippings (Box 90, Folder 10.5)
    On Reel 105 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Infantile paralysis, Queens (Box 90, Folder 10.6)
  - Infantile paralysis. Rockefeller Foundation (Box 90, Folder 10.7)
  - Influenza correspondence (Box 90, Folder 11.1)
  - Influenza; memoranda, etc. (Box 90, Folder 11.2)
  - Influenza Nurses' Emergency Council (Box 90, Folder 11.3)
  - Influenza printed materials (Box 90, Folder 11.4)
  - International Conference of Hygiene and Demography (Box 90, Folder 12)
  - Life Extension Institute (Box 90, Folder 13)
  - Maternity. midwives: correspondence (Box 91, Folder 1.1)
  - Maternity. midwives: English Midwives Act of 1902 (Box 91, Folder 1.2)
  - Maternity. midwives: memoranda, reports. etc. (Box 91, Folder 1.3)
  - Maternity. midwives: printed materials (Box 91, Folder 1.4)
  - Narcotics (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - National Health Council (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - New York City, Department of Health: general (Box 91, Folder 4.1)
  - New York City, Department of Health: Advisory Council (Box 91, Folder 4.2)
  - New York City. Department of Health: Toxin Anti-toxin Campaign (Box 91, Folder 4.3)
  - Pneumonia (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Prostitution, correspondence • (Box 91, Folder 6.1)
  - Prostitution, printed material (Box 91, Folder 6.2)
  - Prostitution, reports (Box 91, Folder 6.3)
  - Prostitution, reports: "Boarding House Type" (Box 91, Folder 6.4)
  - Prostitution, reports: cases (Box 91, Folder 6.5)
  - Prostitution. reports: "Furnished Room Type" (Box 91, Folder 6.6)
    On Reel 106 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Prostitution, reports: Raines Law (Box 91, Folder 6.7)
  - Prostitution, reports: resorts (Box 91, Folder 6.8)
  - Prostitution, reports: "Soda Water Places'" (Box 91, Folder 6.9)
  - Tuberculosis: 1908, 1915, 1922-1923 (Box 91, Folder 7.1)
  - Tuberculosis: 1926-1932 (Box 91, Folder 7.2)
  - Typhoid Fever (Box 91, Folder 8)
- Series X: Russia
  - General, correspondence: 1 (Box 92, Folder 1.1)
  - General, correspondence; 2 (Box 92, Folder 1.2)
  - General; memoranda, reports (Box 92, Folder 1.3)
  - General. printed materials: clippings (Box 92, Folder 1.4)
  - General. printed materials: pamphlets, etc. (Box 92, Folder 1.5)
  - General. photographs (Box 92, Folder 1.6)
  - American Friends Service Committee (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - American Society for Cultural Relations with Russia, 1926-1927 (Box 92, Folder 3.1)
  - American Society for Cultural Relations with Russia, 1928 (Box 92, Folder 3.2)
    On Reel 107 of the Wald Microfilm
  - American Society for Cultural Relations with Russia, 1929 (Box 92, Folder 3.3)
  - American Society for Cultural Relations with Russia, 1930 (Box 92, Folder 3.4)
  - Catherine Breshkovsky. correspondence (Box 93, Folder 1.1)
  - Catherine Breshkovsky; notes. biographical, etc. (Box 93, Folder 1.2)
  - Catherine Breshkovsky. printed materials: clippings (Box 93, Folder 1.3)
  - Catherine Breshkovsky printed materials: pamphlets (Box 93, Folder 1.4)
  - Nikolai V. Chaykovsky (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Friends of Russian Freedom (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Emma Goldman (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Hoershoelman Fund (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Kropotkin (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Ernest Poole (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Pouren-Rudowitz cases (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Reception Committee for Soviet Flyers (Box 93, Folder 9)
    On Reel 108 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Russian-American Industrial Corporation (Box 93, Folder 10)
  - Russian committees and groups (Box 93, Folder 11)
  - Russian Reconstruction Farms (Box 93, Folder 12)
  - Soviet recognition, 1929 (Box 93, Folder 13)
  - Alexander Tchijewsky (Box 93, Folder 14)
- Series XI: Settlements (other than Henry Street)
  - General (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - American Association or Social Workers, 1924-1928 (Box 94, Folder 2.1)
  - American Association of Social Workers, 1929-1933 (Box 94, Folder 2.2)
  - Association of Neighborhood Workers. 1913-1917 (Box 94, Folder 3.1)
  - Association of Neighborhood Workers 1918 (Box 94, Folder 3.2)
  - Association of Neighborhood Workers. 1919 (Box 94, Folder 3.3)
  - Houses; Bronx House. Correspondence (Box 94, Folder 4.1)
  - Houses; Bronx House. minutes and reports (Box 94, Folder 4.2)
  - Houses; camp Rising Sun in Rhinebeck. New York (Box 94, Folder 4.3)
  - Houses; Chicago Commons, Chicago (Box 94, Folder 4.4)
  - Houses; Christodora House (Box 94, Folder 4.5)
  - Houses; "Christodora House News" (Box 94, Folder 4.6)
  - Houses; College Settlement (Box 94, Folder 4.7)
  - Houses; Franklin Street Settlement. Detroit (Box 94, Folder 4.8)
  - Houses; Goodrich Social Settlement, Cleveland (Box 94, Folder 4.9)
  - Houses; Greenwich House (Box 94, Folder 4.10)
  - Houses; Hartley House (Box 94, Folder 4.11)
  - Houses; Hudson Guild (Box 94, Folder 4.12)
  - Houses; Hull House, Chicago (Box 94, Folder 4.13)
  - Houses; Irene Kaufman Settlement. Pittsburgh (Box 94, Folder 4.14)
  - Houses; Kingsley House, Pittsburgh (Box 94, Folder 4.15)
  - Houses; Lennox Hill Neighborhood House (Box 94, Folder 4.16)
  - Houses; The Lighthouse. Philadelphia (Box 94, Folder 4.17)
  - Houses; Lincoln House, Boston (Box 94, Folder 4.18)
    On Reel 109 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Houses; Madison House (Box 94, Folder 4.19)
  - Houses; The Neighborhood House, Montreal (Box 94, Folder 4.20)
  - Houses; The Neighborhood House, San Deigo (Box 94, Folder 4.21)
  - Houses; Protestant Federation (Box 94, Folder 4.22)
  - Houses; Riis Neighborhood Settlement (Box 94, Folder 4.23)
  - Houses; South End House, Boston (Box 94, Folder 4.24)
  - Houses; Stuyvesant Neighborhood House, 1926 (Box 94, Folder 4.25)
  - Houses; Stuyvesant Neighborhood House, 1927-1928 (Box 94, Folder 4.26)
  - Houses; Stuyvesant Neighborhood House, 1929-1930 (Box 94, Folder 4.27)
  - Houses; Stuyvesant Neighborhood House, 1931-1933 (Box 94, Folder 4.28)
  - Houses; Union Settlement (Box 94, Folder 4.29)
  - Houses; University House. Philadelphia (Box 94, Folder 4.30)
  - Houses; University of Chicago Settlement (Box 94, Folder 4.31)
  - Houses; University Settlement (Box 94, Folder 4.32)
  - Houses; University Settlement of Montreal (Box 94, Folder 4.33)
  - Houses; Wright Settlement. Detroit (Box 94, Folder 4.34)
  - Houses; miscellaneous A-G (Box 94, Folder 4.35)
  - Houses; miscellaneous I-W (Box 94, Folder 4.36)
  - National Federation of Settlements, correspondence: 1917-1920 (Box 95, Folder 1.1)
  - National Federation of Settlements. correspondence: 1921-1922 (Box 95, Folder 1.2)
  - National Federation of Settlements, correspondence: 1923-1925 (Box 95, Folder 1.3)
  - National Federation of Settlements, correspondence: 1926 (Box 95, Folder 1.4)
  - National Federation of Settlements, correspondence: 1927 (Box 95, Folder 1.5)
  - National Federation of Settlements. correspondence: 1928 (Box 95, Folder 1.6)
  - National Federation of Settlements, correspondence: 1929 (Box 95, Folder 1.1)
  - National Federation of Settlements. correspondence: 1930 (Box 95, Folder 1.8)
  - National Federation of Settlements. correspondence; 1931 (Box 95, Folder 1.9)
  - National Federation of Settlements, correspondence: 1932 (Box 95, Folder 1.10)
  - National Federation of Settlements. correspondence: 1933 (Box 95, Folder 1.11)
  - National Federation of Settlements, minutes (Box 95, Folder 1.12)
  - National Federation of Settlements, memoranda & reports: no date (Box 95, Folder 1.13)
    On Reel 110 of the Wald Microfilm
  - National Federation of Settlements, memoranda & reports: 1917-1919 (Box 95, Folder 1.14)
  - National Federation of Settlements, memoranda & reports: 1920-1923 (Box 95, Folder 1.15)
  - National Federation of Settlements, memoranda & reports: 1925-1927 (Box 95, Folder 1.16)
  - National Federation of Settlements. memoranda & reports: 1928-1930 (Box 95, Folder 1.11)
  - National Federation of Settlements. memoranda & reports: 1931 (Box 95, Folder 1.18)
  - National Federation of Settlements. memoranda & reports: 1933 (Box 95, Folder 1.19)
  - National Federation of Settlements, printed materials: 1911-1923 and no date (Box 95, Folder 1.20)
  - National Federation of Settlements. printed materials: 1926-1933 (Box 95, Folder 1.21)
  - National Federation of Settlements, boys' work (Box 96, Folder 1.1)
  - National Federation of Settlements. bulletins (Box 96, Folder 1.2)
  - National Federation of Settlements. camp committee (Box 96, Folder 1.3)
  - National Federation of Settlements, group club work: 1931 (Box 96, Folder 1.4)
  - National Federation of Settlements. group club work: 1932 (Box 96, Folder 1.5)
  - National Federation of Settlements. group club work: 1933 (Box 96, Folder 1.6)
  - National Federation of Settlements, group club work 1934 (Box 96, Folder 1.1)
  - National Federation of Settlements, music division (Box 96, Folder 1.8)
  - National Federation of Settlements. "Neighborhood" (magazine) (Box 96, Folder 1.9)
  - National Federation of Settlements, unemployment study: correspondence (Box 96, Folder 1.10)
    On Reel 111 of the Wald Microfilm
  - National Federation of Settlements, unemployment study: reports (Box 96, Folder 1.11)
  - Social Work, correspondence: 1907-1919 (Box 96, Folder 2.1)
  - Social Work. correspondence: 1920-1932 (Box 96, Folder 2.2)
  - Social Work. printed materials: bibliography (Box 96, Folder 2.3)
  - Social Work. printed materials (Box 96, Folder 2.4·)
  - Social Work, Ethical-Social League (Box 96, Folder 2.5)
  - Social Work. National Conference of Social Work (Box 96, Folder 2.6)
  - Social Work. National Social Unit Organization (Box 96, Folder 2.7)
  - Social Work. National Social Workers Exchange (Box 96, Folder 2.8)
  - Social Work. New York Community Trust (Box 96, Folder 2.9)
  - United Neighborhood Houses, correspondence: 1919 (Box 97, Folder 1.1)
  - United Neighborhood Houses, correspondence: 1920-1924 (Box 97, Folder 1.2)
  - United Neighborhood Houses, correspondence: 1925 (Box 97, Folder 1.3)
  - United Neighborhood Houses, correspondence: 1926 (Box 97, Folder 1.4)
  - United Neighborhood Houses, correspondence: 1927 (Box 97, Folder 1.5)
  - United Neighborhood Houses, correspondence: 1928 (Box 97, Folder 1.6)
  - United Neighborhood Houses, correspondence: 1929 (Box 97, Folder 1.7)
  - United Neighborhood Houses, correspondence: 1930-1933 (Box 97, Folder 1.8)
  - United Neighborhood Houses. lists (Box 97, Folder 1.9)
  - United Neighborhood Houses; memoranda. reports. etc. (Box 97, Folder 1.10)
    On Reel 112 of the Wald Microfilm
  - United Neighborhood Houses. minutes: 1919-1920 (Box 97, Folder 1.11)
  - United Neighborhood Houses. minutes: 1921 (Box 97, Folder 1.12)
  - United Neighborhood Houses. minutes: 1922-1929 (Box 97, Folder 1.13)
  - United Neighborhood Houses. printed materials (Box 97, Folder 1.14)
  - United Neighborhood Houses. "Better Times" (magazine): 1919 and no date (Box 97, Folder 1.15)
  - United Neighborhood Houses. "Better Times" (magazine): 1920 (Box 97, Folder 1.16)
  - United Neighborhood Houses, "Better Times" (magazine): 1921-1924 (Box 97, Folder 1.17)
  - United Neighborhood Houses. "Better Times" (magazine): 1925 (Box 97, Folder 1.18)
  - United Neighborhood Houses. "Better Times" (magazine): 1926 (Box 97, Folder 1.19)
  - United Neighborhood Houses. "Better Times" (magazine): 1927-1929 (Box 97, Folder 1.20)
  - United Neighborhood Houses, "Better Times" (magazine): 1930-1933 (Box 97, Folder 1.21)
  - United Neighborhood Houses, Charter Revision Committee: 1922-1923 (Box 97, Folder 1.22)
  - United Neighborhood Houses. Committee of Ten: J931 (Box 97, Folder 1.23)
  - United Neighborhood Houses, Kenyon Bill (1920) (Box 97, Folder 1.24)
  - United Neighborhood Houses. Lusk Committee (1919-1920) (Box 97, Folder 1.25)
  - United Neighborhood Houses. Financial campaign 1933 correspondence (Box 97, Folder 1.26)
  - United Neighborhood Houses. Financial Campaign 1933 reports (Box 97, Folder 1.27)
- Series XII: Oversize
  - Account Book, 1920-1926 (Box 586)